In the last video, we gave
在前面的视频里 我们
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
a mathematical definition of how
解释了怎样用数学来
to represent or how to
定义或者计算
compute the hypotheses used by Neural Network.
神经网络算法的假设
In this video, I like
在这段视频中 我想
show you how to actually
告诉你如何
carry out that computation efficiently, and
高效地进行计算
that is show you a vector rise implementation.
并展示一个向量化的实现方法
And second, and more importantly, I want
更重要的是 我想
to start giving you intuition about
让你们明白为什么
why these neural network representations
这样表示神经网络
might be a good idea and how
是一个好的方法 并且明白
they can help us to learn complex nonlinear hypotheses.
它们怎样帮助我们学习复杂的非线性假设
Consider this neural network.
以这个神经网络为例
Previously we said that
以前我们说
the sequence of steps that we
计算出假设输出
need in order to compute
的步骤
the output of a hypotheses
是左边的这些
is these equations given on
方程 通过这些方程
the left where we compute
我们计算出
the activation values of the
三个隐藏单元的激励值
three hidden uses and then
然后利用
we use those to compute the
这些值来计算
final output of our hypotheses
假设h(x)的最终输出
h of x.  Now, I'm going
接下来 我要
to define a few extra terms.
定义一些额外的项
So, this term that I'm
因此 这里
underlining here, I'm going to
我画线的项
define that to be
把它定义为
z superscript 2 subscript 1.
z上标(2) 下标1
So that we have that
这样一来 就有了
a(2)1, which is this
a(2)1 这个项
term is equal to
等于
g of z to 1.
g(z(2)1)
And by the
顺便说一下
way, these superscript 2, you
这些上标2
know, what that means is that
的意思是
the z2 and this a2
在z(2)和a(2)中
as well, the superscript
括号中的
2 in parentheses means that these
2表示这些值
are values associated with layer
与第二层相关
2, that is with the hidden
即与神经网络中的
layer in the neural network.
隐藏层有关
Now this term here
接下来 这里的项
I'm going to similarly define as
我将同样定义为
z(2)2.
z(2)2
And finally, this last
最后这个
term here that I'm underlining,
我画线的项
let me define that as z(2)3.
我把它定义为z(2)3
So that similarly we have a(2)3
这样 我们有a(2)3
equals g of
等于
z(2)3.
g(z(2)3)
So these z values are just
所以这些z值都是
a linear combination, a weighted
一个线性组合
linear combination, of the
是输入值x0 x1 x2 x3的
input values x0, x1,
加权线性组合
x2, x3 that go into a particular neuron.
它将会进入一个特定的神经元
Now if you look at
现在 看一下
this block of numbers,
这一堆数字
you may notice that that block
你可能会注意到这块
of numbers corresponds suspiciously similar
对应了
to the matrix vector
矩阵向量运算
operation, matrix vector multiplication
类似于矩阵向量乘法
of x1 times the
x1乘以向量x
vector x. Using this observation
观察到一点
we're going to be able to vectorize this computation
我们就能将
of the neural network.
神经网络的计算向量化了
Concretely, let's define the
具体而言 我们定义
feature vector x as usual
特征向量x
to be the vector of x0, x1,
为x0 x1
x2, x3 where x0
x2 x3组成的向量 其中x0
as usual is always equal
仍然等于1
1 and that defines
并定义
z2 to be the vector
z(2)为
of these z-values, you know, of z(2)1 z(2)2, z(2)3.
这些z值组成的向量 即z(2)1 z(2)2 z(2)3
And notice that, there, z2 this
注意 在这里 z(2)
is a three dimensional vector.
是一个三维向量
We can now vectorize the computation
下面 我们可以这样
of a(2)1, a(2)2, a(2)3 as follows.
向量化a(2)1 a(2)2 a(2)3的计算
We can just write this in two steps.
我们只用两个步骤
We can compute z2 as theta
z(2)等于θ(1)
1 times x and that
乘以x
would give us this vector z2;
这样就有了向量z(2)
and then a2 is
然后 a(2)等于
g of z2 and just
g(z(2))
to be clear z2 here, This
需要明白 这里的z(2)是
is a three-dimensional vector and
三维向量 并且
a2 is also a three-dimensional
a(2)也是一个三维
vector and thus this
向量 因此这
activation g. This applies the
里的激励g 将s函数
sigmoid function element-wise to each
逐元素作用于
of the z2's elements. And
z(2)中的每个元素
by the way, to make our notation
顺便说一下 为了让我们
a little more consistent with
的符号和接下来的
what we'll do later, in this
工作相一致
input layer we have the
在输入层 虽然我们有
inputs x, but we
输入x 但我们
can also thing it is
还可以把这些想成
as in activations of the first layers.
是第一层的激励
So, if I defined a1 to
所以 我可以定义a(1)
be equal to x. So,
等于x 因此
the a1 is vector, I can
a(1)就是一个向量了
now take this x here
我就可以把这里的x
and replace this with z2 equals theta1
替换成a(1)
times a1 just by defining
z(2)就等于θ(1)乘以a(1)
a1 to be activations in my input layer.
这都是通过在输入层定义a(1)做到的
Now, with what I've written
现在 就我目前所写的
so far I've now gotten
我得到了
myself the values for a1,
a1 a2 a3的值
a2, a3, and really
并且
I should put the
我应该把
superscripts there as well.
上标加上去
But I need one more
但我还需要一个值
value, which is I also want this a(0)2
我同样需要这个a(2)0
and that corresponds to
它对应于
a bias unit in the
隐藏层的
hidden layer that goes to the output there.
得到这个输出的偏置单元
Of course, there was a
当然 这里也有一个
bias unit here too that,
偏置单元
you know, it just didn't draw
我只是没有
under here but to
画出来 为了
take care of this extra bias unit,
注意这额外的偏置单元
what we're going to do is add
接下来我们
an extra a0 superscript 2,
要额外加上一个a0 上标(2)
that's equal to one, and after
它等于1 这样一来
taking this step we now have
现在
that a2 is going to
a(2)就是一个
be a four dimensional feature
四维的特征向量
vector because we just added
因为我们刚添加了
this extra, you know,
这个额外的
a0 which is equal to
a0 它等于
1 corresponding to the bias unit
1并且它是隐藏层的
in the hidden layer. And finally,
一个偏置单元 最后
to compute the actual
为了计算假设的
value output of our hypotheses, we
实际输出值 我们
then simply need to compute
只需要计算
z3. So z3 is
z(3)  z(3)等于
equal to this term here that I'm just underlining.
这里我画线的项
This inner term there is z3.
这个方框里的项就是z(3)
And z3 is stated
z(3)等于θ(2)
2 times a2 and finally
乘以a(2) 最后
my hypotheses output h of x which
假设输出为h(x)
is a3 that is
它等于a(3)
the activation of my
a(3)是输出层
one and only unit in
唯一的单元
the output layer. So, that's just the real number. You can write it as a3
它是一个实数 你可以写成a(3)
or as a(3)1 and that's g of z3.
或a(3)1 这就是g(z(3))
This process of computing h of x
这个计算h(x)的过程
is also called forward propagation
也称为前向传播(forward propagation)
and is called that because we
这样命名是因为
start of with the activations
我们从
of the input-units and then
输入层的激励开始
we sort of forward-propagate that to the
然后进行前向传播给
hidden layer and compute the activations of the
隐藏层并计算
hidden layer and then we
隐藏层的激励 然后
sort of forward propagate that
我们继续前向传播
and compute the activations of
并计算输出层的激励
the output layer, but this process of computing the activations from the input then
这个从输入层到
the hidden then the output layer,
隐藏层再到输出层依次计算激励的
and that's also called forward propagation
过程叫前向传播
and what we just did is
我们刚刚得到了
we just worked out a vector
这一过程的向量化
wise implementation of this
实现方法
procedure. So, if you
如果你
implement it using these equations
使用右边这些公式实现它
that we have on the right, these
就会得到
would give you an efficient way
一个有效的
or both of the efficient way of
计算h(x)
computing h of x.
的方法
This forward propagation view also
这种前向传播的角度
helps us to understand what
也可以帮助我们了解
Neural Networks might be doing
神经网络的原理
and why they might help us to
和它为什么能够
learn interesting nonlinear hypotheses.
帮助我们学习非线性假设
Consider the following neural network
看一下这个神经网络
and let's say I cover up
我会暂时盖住
the left path of this picture for now.
图片的左边部分
If you look at what's left in this picture.
如果你观察图中剩下的部分
This looks a lot like
这看起来很像
logistic regression where what
逻辑回归
we're doing is we're using
在逻辑回归中 我们用
that note, that's just the
这个节点 即
logistic regression unit and we're
这个逻辑回归单元
using that to make a
来预测
prediction h of x.  And concretely,
h(x)的值 具体来说
what the hypotheses is outputting
假设输出的
is h of x is going
h(x)将
to be equal to g which
等于s型激励函数
is my sigmoid activation function times theta 0
g(θ0
times a0 is equal
xa0
to 1 plus theta 1
+θ1xa1
plus theta 2
+θ2xa2
times a2 plus theta
+θ3xa3)
3 times a3 whether
其中
values a1, a2, a3
a1 a2 a3
are those given by these three given units.
由这三个单元给出
Now, to be actually consistent
为了和我之前的定义
to my early notation. Actually, we
保持一致 需要
need to, you know, fill in
在这里
these superscript 2's here everywhere
还有这些地方都填上上标(2)
and I also have these
同样还要加上这些下标1
indices 1 there because I
因为我只有
have only one output unit, but if you focus on the blue parts of the notation.
一个输出单元 但如果你只观察蓝色的部分
This is, you know, this looks
这看起来
awfully like the standard logistic
非常像标准的
regression model, except that
逻辑回归模型 不同之处在于
I now have a capital theta instead of lower case theta.
我现在用的是大写的θ 而不是小写的θ
And what this is
这样做完
doing is just logistic regression.
我们只得到了逻辑回归
But where the features fed into
但是 逻辑回归的
logistic regression are these
输入特征值
values computed by the hidden layer.
是通过隐藏层计算的
Just to say that again, what
再说一遍
this neural network is doing is
神经网络所做的
just like logistic regression, except
就像逻辑回归 但是它
that rather than using the
不是使用
original features x1, x2, x3,
x1 x2 x3作为输入特征
is using these new features a1, a2, a3.
而是用a1 a2 a3作为新的输入特征
Again, we'll put the superscripts
同样 我们需要把
there, you know, to be consistent with the notation.
上标加上来和之前的记号保持一致
And the cool thing about this,
有趣的是
is that the features a1, a2,
特征项a1 a2
a3, they themselves are learned
a3它们是作为
as functions of the input.
输入的函数来学习的
Concretely, the function mapping from
具体来说 就是从第一层
layer 1 to layer 2,
映射到第二层的函数
that is determined by some
这个函数由其他
other set of parameters, theta 1.
一组参数θ(1)决定
So it's as if the
所以 在神经网络中
neural network, instead of being
它没有用
constrained to feed the
输入特征x1 x2 x3
features x1, x2, x3 to logistic regression.
来训练逻辑回归
It gets to
而是自己
learn its own features, a1,
训练逻辑回归
a2, a3, to feed into the
的输入
logistic regression and as
a1 a2 a3
you can imagine depending on
可以想象 如果
what parameters it chooses for
在θ1中选择不同的参数
theta 1.  You can learn some pretty interesting
有时可以学习到一些
and complex features and therefore
很有趣和复杂的特征 就可以
you can end up with a
得到一个
better hypotheses than if
更好的假设
you were constrained to use
比使用原始输入
the raw features x1, x2 or x3 or if
x1 x2或x3时得到的假设更好
you will constrain to say choose the
你也可以
polynomial terms, you know,
选择多项式项
x1, x2, x3, and so on.
x1 x2 x3等作为输入项
But instead, this algorithm has
但这个算法可以
the flexibility to try
灵活地
to learn whatever features at once, using
快速学习任意的特征项
these a1, a2, a3 in
把这些a1 a2 a3
order to feed into this
输入这个
last unit that's essentially
最后的单元 实际上
a logistic regression here.  I realized
它是逻辑回归
this example is described as
我觉得现在描述的这个例子
a somewhat high level and so
有点高端 所以
I'm not sure if this intuition
我不知道
of the neural network, you know, having
你是否能理解
more complex features will quite
这个具有更复杂特征项的
make sense yet, but if
神经网络 但是
it doesn't yet in the next
如果你没理解
two videos I'm going to
在接下来的两个视频里
go through a specific example
我会讲解一个具体的例子
of how a neural network can
来说明神经网络
use this hidden there to compute
如何利用这个隐藏层
more complex features to feed
计算更复杂的特征
into this final output layer
并输入到最后的输出层
and how that can learn more complex hypotheses.
以及为什么这样就可以学习更复杂的假设
So, in case what I'm
所以 如果我
saying here doesn't quite make
现在讲的
sense, stick with me
你没理解 请继续
for the next two videos and
观看接下来的两个视频
hopefully out there working through
希望它们
those examples this explanation will
提供的例子能够
make a little bit more sense.
让你更加理解神经网络
But just the point O. You
但有一点
can have neural networks with
你还可以用其他类型的图来
other types of diagrams as
表示神经网络
well, and the way that
神经网络中神经元
neural networks are connected, that's called the architecture.
相连接的方式 称为神经网络的架构
So the term architecture refers to
所以说 架构是指
how the different neurons are connected to each other.
不同的神经元是如何相互连接的
This is an example
这里有一个不同的
of a different neural network architecture
神经网络架构的例子
and once again you may
你可以
be able to get this intuition of
意识到这个第二层
how the second layer,
是如何工作的
here we have three heading units
在这里 我们有三个隐藏单元
that are computing some complex
它们根据输入层
function maybe of the
计算一个复杂的函数
input layer, and then the
然后第三层
third layer can take the
可以将第二层
second layer's features and compute
训练出的特征项作为输入
even more complex features in layer three
并在第三层计算一些更复杂的函数
so that by the time you get
这样 在你到达
to the output layer, layer four,
输出层之前 即第四层
you can have even more
就可以利用第三层
complex features of what
训练出的更复杂的
you are able to compute in
特征项作为输入
layer three and so get very interesting nonlinear hypotheses.
以此得到非常有趣的非线性假设
By the way, in a network
顺便说一下 在这样的
like this, layer one, this is
网络里 第一层
called an input layer. Layer four
被称为输入层 第四层
is still our output layer, and
仍然是我们的输出层
this network has two hidden layers.
这个网络有两个隐藏层
So anything that's not an
所以 任何一个不是
input layer or an output
输入层或输出层的
layer is called a hidden layer.
都被称为隐藏层
So, hopefully from this video
我希望从这个视频中
you've gotten a sense of
你已经大致理解
how the feed forward propagation step
前向传播在
in a neural network works where you
神经网络里的工作原理：
start from the activations of
从输入层的激励
the input layer and forward
开始 向前
propagate that to the
传播到
first hidden layer, then the second
第一隐藏层 然后传播到第二
hidden layer, and then finally the output layer.
隐藏层 最终到达输出层
And you also saw how
并且你也知道了如何
we can vectorize that computation.
向量化这些计算
In the next, I realized
我发现
that some of the intuitions in this
这个视频里我讲了
video of how, you know, other certain
某些层是如何
layers are computing complex features of the early layers.
计算前面层的复杂特征项
I realized some of that intuition
我意识到这可能
may be still slightly abstract and kind of a high level.
仍然有点抽象 显得比较高端
And so what I would like
所以 我将
to do in the two videos
在接下来的两个视频中
is work through a detailed example
讨论具体的例子
of how a neural network can
它描述了怎样用神经网络
be used to compute nonlinear
来计算
functions of the input and
输入的非线性函数
hope that will give you a
希望能使你
good sense of the sorts of
更好的理解
complex nonlinear hypotheses we can get out of Neural Networks.
从神经网络中得到的复杂非线性假设